Guide to the Pittsburgh Railways Company Records, 1872-1974 AIS.1974.29
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Labor Relations, 1949-1963; III.
  Series III contains the records of the Pittsburgh Railway Company's relationship with Divisions 85 and 1084 of the Amalgamated Association of Street Electric Railway and Motor Coach Employees of America, 1949 to 1963. Material includes: correspondence and contract agreements with the union; accounts of wage arbitration; conference memoranda; a daily diary on the strike of 1957; and mounted newspaper clippings.
  - Trustees Exhibits/ Wage Arbitration, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Labor Relations, Prior to New Company, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Conference Memoranda, Feb. 18, 1950 - Oct. 6, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Labor Relations, Misc. Matters, 1951-1963 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Labor Relations, Publicity and News Releases, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
  - Labor Relations, Contract, 1951-1952 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Division 1084 Strike, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Labor Negotiations, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence and Agreements with Union, 1952-1963 (Box 10, Folder 11-13)
  - Strike Data, Division 85, 1954, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Wage Negotiation, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Wage Negotiation, Correspondence, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Labor Negotiations, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Labor Negotiations, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Wage Negotiations, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 4-5)
  - Labor Negotiations, Pension Plan Arbitration, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 6-10)
  - Notes of 1957 Strike, Aug. 26, 1957 - Dec. 5, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Labor Negotiations, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - I.B.E.W. Matters, Contract, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Amalgamated Association, Division 85, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Division 85 Retirement and Disability Agreement, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Annual Reports, 1918-1975; IV.
  Series IV contains Annual Reports to the stockholders of the Philadelphia Company, Pittsburgh Railways and Pittway Corporation; Annual reports of the Pittsburgh Railways Company to the Pennsylvania Public Utility Commission; and Annual Report of the Pittsburgh Motor Coach Company to the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania Department of Internal Affairs, Division of Public Utilities. The reports are arranged chronologically by company.
  - Philadelphia Company, 1918-1920 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Philadelphia Company, 1926-1927 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Philadelphia Company, 1928-1930 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Philadelphia Company, 1931-1934 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Philadelphia Company, 1935-1938 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Philadelphia Company, 1939-1942 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Philadelphia Company, 1943-1947 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Philadelphia Company, 1948-1951 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Pittsburgh Railways Company, 1939-1946 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Pittsburgh Railways Company, 1947-1949 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Pittsburgh Railways Company, 1950-1956 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Pittsburgh Railways Company, 1957-1966 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Pittway Corporation, 1967-1975 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - PRC Annual Reports to PA Public Utility Commission, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - PRC Annual Reports to PA Public Utility Commission, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 12-13)
  - PRC Annual Reports to PA Public Utility Commission, 1953 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - PRC Annual Reports to PA Public Utility Commission, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - PRC Annual Reports to PA Public Utility Commission, 1956 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - PRC Annual Reports to PA Public Utility Commission, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - PRC Annual Reports to PA Public Utility Commission, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - PRC Annual Reports to PA Public Utility Commission, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - PRC Annual Reports to PA Public Utility Commission, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Pittsburgh Motor Coach Annual Report to Pennsylvania Public Utility Commission, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Securities and Exchange Commission Hearings, September 7, 1949 - December 20, 1950; V.
  Series V contains the Official Report of Proceedings before the Securities Exchange Commission in re the indebtedness of the Pittsburgh Railways Company. Hearings held in Washington, D.C., September 7, 1949 to December 20, 1950. This series consists of 1,556 mimeograph pages in 13 volumes.
  - Volume 1-13, September 7, 1949 - December 20, 1950 (Box 13, Folder 1-13)
- Federal Court Proceedings, December 31, 1946; VI.
  Series VI contains one volume of records concerning the Pittsburgh Railways Company, Debtor, in reorganization proceedings in the District Court of the United States for the Western District of Pennsylvania at No. 2025. The series includes a report to W.D. George, Trustee, upon Accounting Review of Transactions for the Period January 1, 1902, to May 10, 1938, in Connection with an investigation directed by Order of Court of November 7, 1945.
  - Reorganization Proceedings, December 31, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Property Appraisals, 1918-1954; VII.
  Series VII contains appraisals of Pittsburgh Railways Company land holdings arising from litigation bought by the City of Pittsburgh and certain other municipalities.
  - Engineers Valuation Board, Minutes, March 15, 1918 - August 16, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 15-18)
  - Engineers Valuation Board, Report, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Appraisal of Right of Way, 1918-1919 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Appraisal of Right of Way, Blueprints, 1918-1919 (Box 14, Folder 2-5)
  - Real Estate Transactions, 1918-1930 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Land Appraisals, PRC Properties, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 7-9)
  - Rights of Way Appraisal, November 9, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 10-11)
- Reorganization Plan, 1949-1950; VIII.
  Series VIII contains one volume of records consisting of the combined plan for the Reorganization of the Pittsburgh Railways System Under the Bankruptcy Act and for Discharge under the Public Utility Holding Company Act of 1935 of Philadelphia Company's Guarantees Affecting Pittsburgh Railways Systems Securities This volume is dated July 1, 1949, and amended February 20, 1950 and March 21, 1950.
  - Reorganization Plan, 1949-1950 (Box 14, Folder 12-13)
- Photographs, 1960s; IX.
  Series IX contains photographs of car barns located in different areas of Pittsburgh in the 1960s. Digital reproductions of the collection are available online.
  - Index to Car Barns (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Millvale (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Glenwood (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Mt. Oliver (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Girty's Run Culvert (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Homestead (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Maple Substation (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - McKeesport (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Ingram (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Hays Substation (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Chartiers, Idlewood, Bell Ave. (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous Materials, 1898-1971; X.
  Series X consists of diagrams, leases, reports, construction ledgers, and aerial film footage of Pittsburgh and the surrounding area. The series also includes PCC streetcar brochures and photos of streetcars in Pittsburgh and Cleveland in the late 1960s.
  - Description of Maps of Street Railway Company (Box 15, Folder 10-11)
  - Set of Underlying Leases, Operating and Sale Agreements, and Consolidations (Box 15, Folder 12-16)
  - Route Diagrams, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Report on the Overall Solution to the Transportation Problem of Allegheny Co., 1958 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - PCC Photos, 1965-1971 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - PCC Brochures, 1938, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Accounting Classifications, 1910-1947 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Data on John Bauer and Alfred Shaw, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - A Plan to Move More People by Improved Transit Operation on Existing Streets, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Pittsburgh Railways Telephone Directory, October, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Agreement Between City of Pittsburgh, Philadelphia Company, and PRC, December 20, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Construction Order Ledger, Pittsburgh Railways, January 31, 1902 - March 31, 1904 (Oversize 1)
  - Construction Orders Ledger, Southern Traction Company, November 30, 1900 - January 1, 1902 (Oversize 2)
  - Track and Shop Orders Ledger, United Traction Company, March 31, 1898 - December 6, 1901 (Oversize 3)
  - Total Historical Cost by Group, Pittsburgh Railways Company, 1919 (Oversize 4)
  - Film - Aerial Footage, Pittsburgh (Oversize 4, Reel 1)
  - Film - Aerial Footage, Dormont (Oversize 4, Reel 2)
  - Film - Aerial Footage, Allegheny River Valley (Oversize 4, Reel 3)
  - Film - Aerial Footage, Unknown (Oversize 4, Reel 4-5)
- Safety Awards and Photographs, 1885-1964; XI.
  Series XI contains a collection of safety awards and photographs from Pittsburgh Railways Company originally accessioned earlier as a separate collection but has been combined with this collection as this series. The series includes pamphlets, maps, copies of stocks, and miscellaneous notes.
  - Photos, 1885-1951 (Oversize 4, Folder 26-40)
  - Fuel Dealer's User License, 1952 (Oversize 4, Folder 41)
  - Advertising Federation of America Premier Award, 1932 (Oversize 4, Folder 42)
  - "Giddap and Go" Pamphlet, 1940 (Oversize 4, Folder 43)
  - Plaque - National Traffic Safety Winner, 1932 (Oversize 4, Folder 44)
  - Plaque - Participation in the Transit Journal Maintenance Contest, 1932-1938 (Oversize 5)
  - Viewer Proceedings (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
  - City Planning Maps (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Stenographic Costs, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Copies of Stocks from Various Railways Companies (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Railroad Maps, 1933-1964; XII.
  This series consists of maps showing all or part of the Pittsburgh Railways Company track system, which was primarily located in and around Pittsburgh and Allegheny County, Pennsylvania. It also includes a table listing the types of passenger motor and trailer cars used by the company.
  - Table of Passenger Motor and Trailer Cars, 1902-1964 inclusive, sheets 1-3, 3 items 17.5" x 23" (Map-case 30-7, Folder 1)
  - Map of the Pittsburgh Railways Company system, 1956; 39" x 28.5"
  - Map of South Hills Tunnels, undated; 36" x 63" (Roll 1)
  - Map of the Pittsburgh Railways Company sytem, including an inset map of "Sub-Plan A" (Downtown Pittsburgh), 1935; 57.5" x 39.5"
  - Map of the Pittsburgh Railways Company system of underlying companies, 1934; 73" x 42"
  - Index to construction orders, maintenance charges, track orders and direct charges paid for by the lessee and inventoried for the lessor, prior to March 1, 1913, with accompanying map, 1933; 59" x 40" (Roll 2)
  - Index to construction orders and way orders affected by construction orders, covering replacements, additions and abandonments, March 1, 1913 to January 1, 1924, with accompanying map, 1933; 59" x 40"
  - Index of way orders considered between 1918 and 1924, unaffected by construction orders, with accompanying map, 1933; 59" x 40"